wfp.org 2016-05-13

# Privacy Policy | WFP | United Nations World Food Programme - Fighting Hunger Worldwide

The World Food Programme is committed to the privacy of individuals who visit and interact with [www.wfp.org](http://www.wfp.org/ "www.wfp.org")  (the “User/s”), and follows the privacy policy outlined below.  This privacy policy applies to all World Food Programme sites - that is all sites within the "wfp.org" domain name (the “Site”).  

## Personally Identifiable Information 

Visitors are not asked to provide any personally identifiable information to access the Site. Users may be asked to share their email address to subscribe to email alerts or newsletters. In this event, the World Food Programme will store this information securely and will not share, rent or sell it to anyone other than WFP partner organizations. We reserve the right to share names, addresses, and account history with our affiliated local partners such as World Food Program USA and WFP Italia for purposes that include provision to you of information on fundraising activities and appeals for donations. In no case will any sensitive financial information be shared. See below for the use of information related to online donations.  

## Non-personally identifiable information 

By accessing the Site, certain information such as Internet protocol (IP) addresses, navigation through the Site, the browser used and the time spent, along with other similar information, will be stored on our servers and on a third party analytics software.  This information is treated confidentially.

The purpose of this data collection is to understand better the preferences of the Site’s visitors and improve their experience on our pages. This information is never connected with any personal information that visitors supply to us if they register on our Site.  

## Use of cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the Site.

By setting a cookie, the World Food Programme will remember the User the next time he/she visits the Site and therefore the World Food Programme will not have to ask questions that the User has already answered (like address information).

The User is always free to decline our cookies if his/her browser permits, although in that case he/she may not be able to use certain features on the site and may be required to re-enter information more frequently to use certain services on the Site.

## Donations to the World Food Programme 

The World Food Programme requests information from the User on its donation form. Here the User must provide contact information (like name and address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used to conduct the transaction and help us better manage donors. If we have trouble processing a donation, this information is also used to contact the User. The World Food Programme will store this information securely and will not share it, rent or sell it to anyone other than WFP partner organizations. We reserve the right to share names, addresses, and account history with our affiliated local partners such as World Food Program USA and WFP Italia for purposes that include provision to you of information on fundraising activities and appeals for donations. In no case will any sensitive financial information be shared.   

## Correction and Updating Personal Information 

A User may modify personally identifiable information (such as zip code or email address) by logging into his/her account which can be done through the top of the donation section of the WFP Site.   

## Opting-out 

Users may elect to receive communications such as newsletters and other material from WFP. If they do, they will have the opportunity to stop receiving such communications at any time by logging into their account from the top of the donation section of the WFP Site and editing their contact preferences or by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the emails.  

## Notification of Changes 

If the World Food Programme decides to change its privacy policy, WFP will post those changes to this page so Users are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it.  

## **Contact Us**

****If you have any questions or concerns about the World Food Programme privacy policy please use the contact form located here:[www.wfp.org/contact](http://www.wfp.org/contact)  

Mailing address:

Via C.G.Viola 68  
Parco dei Medici  
00148 - Rome - Italy

## Links to other sites – Disclaimer 

The Site contains hypertext links to other sites. The World Food Programme assumes no responsibility for those sites including the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.  

## Privileges and Immunities

Nothing in or relating to this privacy policy or this Site shall be deemed a waiver of any of the privileges and immunities of the World Food Programme under the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations and the Convention on the Privileges and Immunities of the Specialized Agencies.

## Content Sharing Terms

By submitting the video content to the World Food Programme (WFP), you: (i) represent and warrant that you are of legal age of consent in the jurisdiction of your domicile; (ii) grant WFP a non-exclusive, worldwide, perpetual, irrevocable,  royalty-free  sublicenseable and transferable license to use, display, distribute, reproduce, modify, remix, transcode, excerpt, adapt, prepare derivative works of and compilations, publicly perform and publicly display such video content in any media format or medium for any purpose whatsoever in connection with WFP activities; (iii) represent and warrant that the video content is original or that you hold the necessary rights to publish the video content you submit and grant WFP the license hereunder; and (iv) agree to indemnify and hold WFP, its officers, agents and employees harmless from any claim or loss made by any third party due to or arising out of video content you submit.
